Okay, so in this video we're going to
discuss the risk register.
The risk register is considered to be an
output of the process
called Identify Risk.
So one of the 49 Pinbox six
processes is Identify Risk and
the risk register is considered
as an output of that process.
It's an artifact, right?
Again, most outputs of those pinbox six
processes are artifacts, right?
They're documents.
And this is a very, very important
artifact, very important document.
And it's basically going to be documenting
all of the risks on the project.
And you are documenting all risks that
you've identified.
So this is a very simple example then of a
risk register.
Now this is not necessarily a PMI approved
template, right, as such, right?
PMI do not necessarily have templates for
all of their artifacts.
What PMI are doing is setting standards.
They're saying this is a
kind of information that
you're expecting to
document in these artifacts.
Now, how you actually want to lay out,
how you actually want to show it,
that's entirely up to you.
So this is just a very simple example then
of a risk register.
So the risk register is essentially going
to contain all of the details regarding
the risk, as many, as much detail as you
see fit.
And you as a project manager, you,
your team, you're going to determine what
we're going to be documenting in the risk
register.
What is our risk register going to look
like?
And really, it's nothing more than just a
spreadsheet, as you can see, right?
You may have a risk ID, right,
each risk.
I mean, you're going to be
identifying potentially thousands
of risks depending on the
size and nature of your project.
So you may have a risk ID.
You're definitely going to have a
description of the risk.
Right.
What is this risk?
You may identify the probability and the
impact.
So the probability and the impact could be
from a quantitative perspective,
a quantitative value, or it could be a
qualitative value.
A qualitative value would be things like
high, medium low, scale of 1 to 10.
So what's the probability of this risk
occurring?
It's a high probability.
What's the impact?
It's a low impact.
That would be the qualitative,
or on a scale of 1 to 10.
On a scale of 1 to 10, I think the
probability of this risk is maybe a six,
on a scale of 1 to 10, the impact if it
occurs will be an 8.
So you may do it from a qualitative
perspective, or you may do it from a
quantitative perspective where you're
actually adding in a dollar value.
What's the probability of this risk
occurring?
It would be in a percentage.
Oh, there's a 30% chance that this risk
might occur.
What's impact if it occurs?
Oh, there's a $20,000 impact.
So the qualitative is
just arbitrary values, high,
medium low, scale of 1
to 10 and that kind of thing.
Now, the example that I gave you just now
from the qualitative, right, on a scale of
1 to 10, what's the probability,
on a scale of 1 to 10, what's the impact?
Well, where is that defined?
If I say on a scale of 1
to 10, the probability of
this risk occurring is a 7,
well, what does that mean?
What does that exactly mean?
That has to be defined somewhere.
and that's going to be defined in the risk
management plan.
So remember, a management plan is going to
be documenting procedures.
So the risk management plan is going to be
documenting the definition then of
probability and impact using these
arbitrary values.
But if it's a quantitative value,
right, so there's a 50% probability that
we may end up spending an additional
$20,000.
Well, you know, that's an absolute value.
So, UMA then, you know, what's the result
of that?
There's another column
here for risk score,
or it could be EMV,
expected monetary value.
So again, what does the risk score mean?
What does the EMV mean, expected monetary
value?
So if it's a qualitative side,
probability and impact arbitrary values,
right, then probability times impact will
be the score, the risk score.
If it's a quantitative value, right,
so you're adding a dollar value.
value, the probability and the impact will
be a percentage times the actual value,
times the impact, which will be the EMV,
expected monetary value.
We have videos on qualitative risk
analysis, where we are using these
arbitrary values, high, medium,
low scale of 1 to 10.
We have separate videos on quantitative
analysis, where we're actually adding in a
dollar value and calculating the EMV,
the expected monetary value.
We also have videos
on all of these other items
that we're going to be
talking about as well.
So the category of risk, that's going to
be documented here.
What's going to trigger that risk?
And then a separate video,
we're going to be talking
about the different
risk response strategies.
Now that we've identified the risk,
well, how do we respond to that risk?
Contingency reserve as
well, remember contingency
reserves is money that
you've set aside for known risks.
So you've identified these
risks here, how much money are
putting in contingency reserves
in case those risks materialises.
And the last column here is a risk owner.
So every risk has to have a risk owner.
So who is responsible for this risk?
Now that we've identified it, now that who
could be an individual
or it could be a team.
However, someone needs to be responsible,
right?
So exactly the same way as how we have
issues or rather we have an issue owner,
right then we will have a risk owner as
well.
So this is just a very, very simple
example here of a risk register.
So the risk register is going to be
documenting all risks on your project,
regardless of what the probability is,
what the impact is, whether it's high
probability or low probability,
whether it's a high impact or low impact.
You've identified a risk.
You know, somebody
has identified a risk is
going to be documented
here in the risk register.
Thank you.